opinionsample.com 2019-12-18

# Privacy policy

Our privacy policy sets out how we handle personal data. We are aware of the importance to users of how personal data are handled and we assure you that we observe all relevant legal requirements. We consider the protection of your privacy to be of paramount importance. For this reason, compliance with the legal requirements on data privacy is self-evident. 

### Contact

Yuno is a trademark of Dalia Research GmbH, registered in Germany.

Nico Jaspers, PhD   
Lobeckstraße 30/35  
Entrance H, 2nd floor  
10969 Berlin  
Email: [contact@yunosurveys.com](mailto:contact@yunosurveys.com)

## Data protection officer

External Data Protection Officer   
ePrivacy GmbH  
represented by Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer  
Große Bleichen 21, 20354 Hamburg

For all requests concerning the security of your data you can contact our data protection officer at email address dpo@yunosurveys.com. If you have a particularly sensitive request, please contact our external data protection officer by post, as communication by email can always show security gaps. 

## Personal Data

We process the following personal data: age, gender, email, mobile number, intention to buy a car, level of education, ethnicity, household income, job title, employment status, number of employees of employer, industry of employer, country, region, city, postal code, latitude, longitude, dma code, IP, device kind, device version, device platform, user agent, browser language, evercookie uuid, device fingerprint (relevant id, augur, true sample) 

## Legal basis

Your data are handled according to the following legal provisions: 

  * With regard to data communicated in forms, surveys, etc. with your consent, Art. 6(1) (a) GDPR
  * With regard to services you use for the performance of a contract, Art. 6(1)(b) GDPR
  * Otherwise, with particular regard to statistical data and online identifiers based on legitimate interests, Art 6(1)(f) GDPR (see below)

## Legitimate interests

When handling your data, we pursue the following legitimate interests: 

  * Improving our service
  * Protecting against misuse
  * Statistics
  * Customer acquisition and offer of services
  * Communication with business partners and customers

## Data sources

Unless otherwise specified, we obtain the data from you (including via devices used by you). If we do not collect personal data directly from you, we will also inform you from which source the personal data originates and, if applicable, whether it originates from public accessible sources. 

## Retention period

We retain your data, 

  * if you have consented to this as part of processing, until such time as you withdraw your consent
  * if we need the data to undertake an agreement, until such time as the contractual relationship with you ceases or legal retention periods expire
  * if we use the data on the basis of a legitimate interest, until such time as your overriding interest obliges us to delete or anonymise them

## Purposes of use

Personal data will only be collected by us to the extent and for the purpose for which you provide the data to us, e.g. for registration. 

We use and store your personal data as part of our services for the following purposes only if you have provided us with your express consent: 

  * Statistical and aggregate form for market and opinion research
  * Gather profiling information about you so we can better match you with specific surveys
  * Contact you to invite you to participate in surveys or other market research programs
  * Update our records of your personal data
  * Manage our incentives programs and fulfill your requests for such incentives
  * Distribution of your profile information, including personal information, for market research purposes
  * To send you marketing newsletters
  * Mobile number is used as an additional method of user verification and for fraud prevention purposes

We use your personal information only within the company and forward it only to those companies that are involved in performing the contracts concluded with you or otherwise involved in providing the relevant service. Otherwise, your personal information will not be forwarded to third parties unless you have given your express consent for this or unless we are obliged to disclose it, for example, at the direction of a court or administrative authority. 

We may share your personal information and/or social-demographic information, including, without limitation, a unique identification number ("UID"), postal code, gender, marital status, education, ethnicity/race (where permitted by applicable law), employment related information, and non-personally identifiable information on household members, with third party sample/market research companies (individually each a "Third Party MR Company" and collectively the "Third Party MR Companies") for various purposes, including, without limitation, identifying third party survey opportunities for you, disclosing such data elements to clients of the Third Party MR Companies for audience measurement services, appending such data elements to completed client surveys and delivering the appended survey data to clients of the Third Party MR Company(ies) for analytical or research purposes, facilitating your participation in a third party survey(s), tracking your survey activity, addressing survey quality issues, and incentive/reward fulfillment. 

As some of these third parties may reside outside of the European Union/European Economic Area, your personal data and non-personal data may be transferred, processed, and stored outside of the country in which you reside. 

If you are eligible for a client survey opportunity offered through a Third Party MR Company, the Third Party MR Company will provide your unique identification number and a survey link to us and we will invite you to participate in the client survey through our website, email, website notifications or mobile notifications. We will not share your name, email address, or phone number with the Third Party MR Companies. In connection with the sharing of your information with a Third Party MR Company, your information may be transferred and stored outside of your country of residence, including, without limitation, in the United States (Acknowledged country with a Privacy-Shield-Certification), and by agreeing to this privacy policy you are agreeing to the processing and exportation of your personal information as set forth in this Section. Your participation in such survey opportunities does not entitle you to any benefits offered by, or membership with, the Third Party MR Companies. 

In individual cases, an additional statement of informed consent will be requested from you. These are: Ethnic origin, Religious beliefs, Political opinions, Sexual Orientation 

## Data security

We have taken extensive technical and organisational measures to secure your data against potential risks, such as unauthorised login or access, unauthorised perusal, amendment or distribution, as well as against loss, deletion or misuse. 

In order to protect your personal data against unauthorised access by third parties when being transmitted, we secure data transmissions, if necessary, using SSL encryption. This is a standard encryption procedure for online services, particularly for the Internet. 

## Cookies

Cookies are small files that your browser stores on your PC in a directory designated specifically for this purpose. These cookies can be used e.g. to find out whether you have already visited a website. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. Nevertheless, you can change the settings in your browser, so that no cookies can be stored or so that your explicit agreement is required before any cookies are stored. You can also delete previously set cookies at any time. Please note that disabling cookies may result in your use of our website being restricted. 

We need cookies for the following purposes: 

### Web analysis

Like almost all website operators, we use analytical tools in the form of tracking software to ascertain the number of users using our website and how frequently they visit. 

To enable us to optimise our website and our service, we use Google Analytics, which is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses what are known as "cookies": these are text files stored on your computer and used to analyse your website usage. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) will be sent to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymisation is enabled on this website, within member states of the European Union, or in other states that are party to the agreement on the European Economic Area Google first abbreviates your IP address. The full IP address will only be transmitted in exceptional circumstances to one of Google's servers in the USA, where it will then be abbreviated. Google will use this information on behalf of our website operator to analyse your use of the website in order to compile reports about website activities for the website operator and to perform other services connected with the use of the website and of the Internet. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged or combined with other data by Google. You can prevent cookies from being stored by applying the appropriate settings in your browser software; please note, however, that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their full extent. 

You may also prevent Google from collecting data generated by the cookie referring to your website usage (including your IP address), and from processing these data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de . As an alternative to the browser add-on or within browsers on mobile devices, please click on this link to prevent Google Analytics from collecting data in this website in future (the opt-out only works in this browser, and only for this domain). This stores an opt-out cookie on your device. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you need to click on this link again. Further information is available at tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de or at www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html(general information on Google Analytics and data protection). 

This website uses Jetpack (formerly WordPress.com-Stats), a tool for statistically analysing visitor access, run by Automattic Inc. (132 Hawthorne St., San Francisco, CA, 94107, USA), using tracking technology from Quantcast Inc. (201 3rd St, Floor 2, San Francisco, CA 94103-3153, USA). Jetpack uses what are known as "cookies". These are text files stored on your computer that are used to analyse your website usage. The information on your use of this Internet service generated by the cookie is stored on a server in the USA. The IP address is anonymised immediately after processing and prior to being saved. You can prevent the installation of cookies by applying the appropriate settings in your browser software. Please note, however, that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their full extent. You can opt out of Quantcast collecting and using your data in the future by setting an opt-out cookie on your browser. To do this, follow this link and click on "Click here to opt-out": www.quantcast.com/opt-out. If you delete all cookies on your computer, you will need to reinstall the opt-out cookie. 

## Google Fonts

This site uses web fonts provided by Google to uniformly display fonts. When you open a page, your browser loads the required Google Fonts into your browser cache to display texts and fonts correctly. 

To do this, your browser must connect to Google's servers. This gives Google knowledge that our website has been accessed via your IP address. The use of Google Fonts is in the interest of a consistent and user-friendly presentation of our website. This represents a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. 

If your browser does not support Google Fonts, your computer uses a standard font. Further information about Google Fonts can be found at <https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq> and in Google's privacy policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

## Usage-related advertising

To optimise advertising for you based on your browsing interests, we have authorised the following companies to collect usage data. You will find further data privacy information on the website of each of these companies relating to the services that it offers: 

## Social Networks

### Facebook

Facebook is operated by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA and is available online at www.facebook.de . Individual social media plugins feature one of the Facebook logos or the extension 'Facebook Social Plugin'. A list of the visuals and functions of the individual plugins can be seen here: developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins. Whenever you visit a page on our website which contains one of these social media plugins, your browser will establish a direct connection with the Facebook servers. The content of the social media plugins are transferred from Facebook to your browser, which incorporates them into the website. We therefore have no influence over the scope of the data which Facebook collects using its social media plugins, and are able to provide information to you about this only to the best of our knowledge: Because the social media plugin is embedded, Facebook is informed that you have visited the page of our website in question, even if you are not a registered user of Facebook or are not logged into Facebook at the time. This information is transferred from your browser along with your IP address to a Facebook server in the USA and stored there. According to information provided by Facebook, only an anonymised IP address is stored for non-registered users in Germany. If you are logged into Facebook, Facebook can directly attribute it to your Facebook account whenever you visit our website. Facebook receives information about your visit to our website, regardless of whether you interact with the social media plugins. If you interact with the social media plugins (for example, click the 'Like' button or leave a comment), the relevant information is transferred by your browser directly to Facebook and stored there. Additionally, the information is published on Facebook and displayed to your Facebook friends. To find out about the purpose and scope of this data gathering, further processing and use of the data by Facebook, as well as your rights and options for protecting your privacy, please review the Facebook privacy policy www.facebook.com/about/privacy . If you are a registered Facebook user, and prefer Facebook not to collect data about you via our website and connect it with your membership data stored at Facebook, you must log out of Facebook before visiting our website. It is also possible to block the social media plugins using add-ons for your browser, such as the Facebook Blocker: webgraph.com/resources/facebookblocker 

### Youtube

This website uses plugins from Youtube.de/Youtube.com which is operated by Youtube, LLC (901 Cherry Avenue, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA). If you visit a website that contains such a plugin, your browser establishes a direct connection with the YouTube servers. These plugins transfer data to the YouTube servers about which websites you have visited. If you are logged in as a member of YouTube, YouTube attributes this information to each of your personal user accounts on these platforms. When using these plugins (for example, clicking the 'Play' button on a video or leaving a comment), this information is attributed to your YouTube user account, which you can prevent by logging out of your account before using the plugin. For more information, please review the privacy policy: www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy

### Twitter

This website uses buttons for the Twitter service which is offered by Twitter Inc. (1355 Market St., Suite 900, San Francisco, CA, 94103, USA). These plugins can be identified by terms such as 'Twitter', 'tweet' and/or the Twitter logo. They make it possible, among other things, to share a comment or a page of this website via Twitter. When you visit a website which contains such a button, your browser establishes a direct connection with the Twitter servers. The content of the Twitter button is transferred directly from Twitter to your browser. We therefore have no influence over the scope of the data collected by Twitter via this plugin, and can only provide information on this to you to the best of our knowledge. Log data (for example, the user's IP address and previously visited websites, etc.) are transferred to Twitter. For more information, please review the Twitter privacy policy: twitter.com/privacy 

### XING

The "XING Share Button" is installed on this website. When accessing this site, your browser will briefly connect to the servers of XING AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg ("XING"), which establishes the "XING Share Button" functions (in particular the calculation/display of the counter value). XING does not store any of your personal data regarding access to this website. XING in particular does not store any IP addresses. No analysis will be made of your browsing behaviour using cookies in connection with the "XING Share Button". Current data protection information on the "XING Share Button" and additional information can be found here: www.xing.com/app/share?op=data_protection

### LinkedIn

Plug-ins from LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (LinkedIn) are incorporated in this website. The LinkedIn plug-ins are identifiable from the LinkedIn logo or the "Share Button" on this website. If you visit this website, a direct connection will be generated between your browser and the LinkedIn server through the plug-in. In this way, LinkedIn receives information on the fact that you visited this website with your IP address. If you click on the LinkedIn "Share Button" while you are logged in to your LinkedIn account, you can link the contents of this web page to your LinkedIn profile. In this way, LinkedIn can allocate the visit to this website to your user account. Please note that we as website operators receive no knowledge of the content of the data transferred or their use by LinkedIn. You can find details on data collection (its purpose, extent, further processing and use) as well as on your rights and the possibility to amend settings in LinkedIn's privacy policy. The LinkedIn policy can be found at www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy . 

### AddThis

Plugins from Add This LLC (1595 Spring Hill Rd, Suite 300, Vienna, VA 22182, USA) are integrated into this website. These 'AddThis' plugins enable you to place bookmarks and/or share interesting website content. When you visit this website, the plugin creates a direct connection between your browser and the AddThis server, so that AddThis receives, among other things, information that you have visited this website from your IP address. Cookies are used whenever you use AddThis. The data generated (such as time of access or browser language) are transferred to AddThis in the USA and stored there. For more information about the data gathered and how it is processed by AddThis, as well as the option to prevent use of your data, please visit: [ www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy ](https://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)

## Third-party services

We use third-party services for various functions on our website. 

## Rights of the data subject

Right to access, rectification, right to object, to complaint, erasure and blockage. 

  * You have the right to request information about whether and which personal data is processed by our company. You also have the right to demand that your personal data is rectified or amended.
  * Under certain circumstances, you have the right to request that your personal data should be deleted.
  * Under certain circumstances, you have the right to demand that the processing of your personal data should be restricted.
  * You can withdraw your consent to the processing and use of your data completely or partially at any time with future application.
  * You have the right to obtain your personal data in a common, structured and mechanically readable format.
  * If you have any questions, comments, complaints or requests in connection with our statement on data protection and the processing of your personal data, you can also contact our data protection officer in detail.
  * You also have the right to complain to the responsible supervisory authority if you believe that the processing of your personal data is in violation of the legislation.

## CCPA

The California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) is a new data privacy law which applies to certain businesses that collect personal information from California residents. The new law goes into effect on January 1, 2020. 

### Your Rights and Choices

The CCPA provides consumers with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes consumer CCPA rights. 

_Right to erasure:_ You have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collect from you and retained. 

_Right to access/portability:_ You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. 

_Right to request additional information about data collection:_ You have the right to request that we disclose the categories of personal information that Dalia collected, disclosed and sold. 

_Right to request information about sales or disclosures:_ You have the right to request that we disclose the categories of personal information that Dalia collected, disclosed and sold. 

_Right to not be discriminated against if exercising rights:_ We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. We will not deny you goods or services, charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties, provide you a different level or quality of goods or services, or suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services. 

### Methods for submitting consumer rights requests

This section describes how to exercise your CCPA rights. 

You can submit and exercise consumer and privacy rights in the data & privacy page of our website. You can request us not to sell your personal Information by accessing the data & privacy page, in the section "How do I Prevent my data from being sold?" 

Dalia may sell your personal information and aggregate the information provided by your survey answers and by your device, in order to share it with third parties through an online dashboard and/or CSV files. Examples of the type of information we may sell and/or aggregate include survey answers, information about demographics, trustscore, IP, device kind. 

## Contact

You reach us as follows: 

Yuno, Datenschutz, Lobeckstr. 30-35, Entrance H, 2nd floor, 10969 Berlin. 

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding Yuno's privacy practices or in case you want to exercise your privacy rights you may contact Yuno by email or by post. If you are resident in the European Union and you are dissatisfied with how we have managed a complaint you have submitted to us, you are entitled to contact your local data protection supervisory authority. 

## Requirement or obligation to provide data

Insofar as this is not expressly stated, when data are collected, the provision of data is neither required nor obligatory. 

## Date of this privacy policy

04 April 2019 

We reserve the right to make amendments at any time to this privacy policy for future effect. 

This privacy policy has been compiled with the assistance of the ePrivacy GmbH data privacy statement generator.
